CURRICULUM VITAE

Satyanarayan Khandelwal

B.E.(Comp. Sci. & Engg.)

khandelwal.s.r@gmail.com 9850425766

Profile Summary:

Sun Certified Web Component Developer with 12.3 years of experience as software developer in Java, Servlet, JSP, JDBC, Struts, Spring, Hibernate and Web Services. Determined performer with comprehensive analytical and problem solving, excellent communication skills and strong desire to learn who believes in sincerity.

Educational Qualification:

• B.E. (Computer Sci. & Engg.)

Certification:

- 1. Sun Certified Web Component Developer (SCWCD)
- 2. Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP)

Employment Summary:

Last employed with L and T Infotech, Pune from May 2017 to April 2019.

Technical Skills:

Languages : Java 1.8

Technical Framework: Struts 1.1, Spring 2.5 (Core, Web Flow, AOP), Hibernate

Web Technologies : JSF, Servlet2.3, JSP1.2, JSTL, HTML, XML

Web Server : Apache Tomcat5.0

Application Server : Oracle Application Server, Websphere Application Server, Weblogic

Server

RDBMS : MySQL, Oracle9i

IDE : MyEclipse, JDeveloper10G

Version Control System: Tortoise CVS, VSS (Visual Source Safe), SVN

Professional Experience

L and T Infotech, Pune From May 2017 - April 2019

Project title : Nordea Life and Pensions

Designation: Project Lead

Module : Actuary (Premium Calculation)

Description: This application is basically for insurance services like risk, capital redemption and pension-based product. In this application as per customer requirement policies are created and all

data of this insurance product is stored in a LIS system. As per transaction, batches are run; data gets modified and validated for different policies with different customers.user.

Technical Environment: Java, Struts, Hibernate, Maven, Eclipse, Jira, Confluence, Oracle **Responsibilities:**

Created API documents and implemented REST services. Handled post launch production support data fix up and performed root cause analysis for defects of production. Reducing technical debts and practicing efficient coding methods. Worked on JIRA for tracking and managing stories (tasks) assigned, Bit Bucket for maintain Source Code, Confluence for documentation and Merging the code using Git Stash tool. Worked in a highly dynamic AGILE and SAFE environment and participated in scrum and sprint meetings.

Project title : MMC (March and Maclennan)
Duration : June 2017 till March 2018

Designation: Project Lead

Module : MMR – Mags Mobile Redesign

Description: This project was redesign of the existing MAGs application in order to make it work on mobile. Fucionality wise it was relate to user enrollment for MMC client and various operations like viewing the certificate, editing client details, making online payments for the due amount, viewing claim details, making various forms and services available to end user.

Technical Environment: Apache Wicket, Core Java(1.7), Weblogic, Oracle, Perforce **Responsibilities:**

Responsible for development of new pages, application is based on the customized framework(GCF) on the top of Apache Wicket framework.

Configuration based development is being done in this project and I was responsible for understanding the needed configuration for the new pages and putting it into configuration files.

Functional testing, peer testing, peer code review

During the testing cycle fixing defects.

Synechron Technologies, Pune

Project title : Eshare (DOCMAN) - HSBC
Duration : Oct. 2016 till Apr. 2017

Designation : Technical Lead **Module** : **eshare Admin**

Description: eShare admin is a document management system for HSBC. All the confidential documents are managed by using eShare application. This uses filenet on the backend.

Eshare admin is responsible for management of folder. Eshare admin enable creation and edit of folder. Folder can be approved or rejected. Access to created folder can be maintained on user basis. Various level of access are managed. Folders can be archived and unarchived. Blocking of folders is also done on the basis of expiry date.

Technical Environment: Project involves writing new Controller classes, modifying existing java controller classes. This involves use of Spring, Hibernate, Oracle, Core Java.

Responsibilities:

Responsible for writing new Controller classes, modifying existing java controller classes. I participate

in defect fixing by analyzing the cause for the defect and applying fixes.

Responsible for writing unit test cases for the new classes and methods introduced. Performs peer review.

Accenture India Pvt. Ltd, Pune

Project title : UBS

Duration : Sep. 2015 – Sep 2016

Designation: Team Lead

Module : ZEUS (Risk Management) – WM Analytics

Description: Module is related wealth management analysis. Here there are lot of analysis need to be performed and this is based on the various data which need to be gathered from various source.

Technical Environment: Team is responsible for writing loader, wrapper and calculator. Most of the code is based on core java, with every component many db script needs to be written. This is involves enough PL/SQL work.

Responsibilities

I am responsible for writing loader, rollback and controller for collecting data from various sources and after validation and transformation putting into main database schema. Rollback and Controller are used for post loader activities. In case of failure rollback is applied and controller is used to raise alert in case of validation failures.

Project title : OP Pohjola

Duration: Feb. 2015 till Sep 2015.

Designation: Team Lead

Module : Fund Management

Description : Module includes functionality for purchase, sell and replace of funds for the OP

bank customer.

Technical Environment: Team was responsible for writing web services to fulfill various functional requirements. I was involved in writing these web services.

Responsibilities :

I was a part of back end team, needed to get trained on JAX-WS and leading a team for writing the SOAP service as per the technical design document. Writing SOAP services using bottom - up approach. Also writing/creating clients for few external services and implementing business logic.

Project title : Intesa Sanpaolo -Integrated Multichannel

Duration: Dec. 2014 till Feb 2015.

Designation: Team Lead

Module : Integrated Multichannel

Description: Module is a part of loan simulation. Provide the details to online customer about his/her loan eligibility, loan limit etc based on input from client.

Technical Environment: Application was divided into two front end and back end. Front end was based on core java, spring MVC and JSP. In backend JAX-WS was used to write the SOAP services.

Responsibilities :

I was a part of back end team, needed to get trained on JAX-WS and leading a team for writing the SOAP service as per the technical design document. Writing SOAP services using bottom - up approach. Also

writing/creating clients for few external services and implementing business logic.

Project title : Tryg shared system AO
Duration : Feb. 2014 till Nov. 2014.

Designation: Team Lead

Module : NetInsurance (www.tryg.dk)

Description: Application is a part of online portal for Tryg Insurance, Denmark. On this portal there is a self service facility is available. This enable user to buy insurance online. Likewise many other features are available.

Technical Environment: Application tryg.dk is composed of many components like tridion, java, lotus notes, on the backend side mainframe, Siebel. Netisurace module is based on Struts1 and Struts2. For UI Jsp and web service to make the service call to various other component.

Responsibilities

I lead the java team for onsite visit in the month of May 2014.

I was responsible for all the deliverable for the module. I worked on both the front, team management and delivery. Played significant role in forming good relations with onsite SME and client.

I successfully understand the processes to be followed, was interfacing for the client communication.

Project title : Zurich Financial Services (Italy, Milan)

Duration: June. 2011 till Oct. 2013.

Designation: Team Lead

Module : NPP(Next Product Platform)

Description : Application was replacing the legacy system build in Cobol at Zurich. Zurich has hundreds of insurance products and NPP is the new system in J2EE. Earlier it started with general insurance (GI) product to be implemented. Application was responsible for Policy issuance flow, including, consultations, appendix, proposal, upgrading proposal to policy, substitution.

Technical Environment : Application based on Spring framework, including various module like MVC, Webflow, Core, AOP and database transaction management. JSF and Richfaces are used for page creation and data population. DROOLs for writing and separating the conditional logic from the java files. Microsoft sql server—as a database.

Responsibilites

I was the first person to start working on this application from the offshore, for the same I went to Milan(Italy) for KT.

After coming back established the team of 4 members and was responsible all the deliverables going from IDC.

I did involve writing code for new developments, fixing the defect.

All the laterals in the team were trained by me also prepared few KT documents towards the same.

Was responsible for guiding the team members towards the technical problems, letting them understand the processes to be followed, was interfacing for the client communication.

Mastek Limited, Pune

Duration : Jun. 2010 to May 2011. **Designation** : Sr. Software Engineer.

IBM India Pvt. Ltd., PUNE

Duration : Mar. 2010 to Jun 2010.

Designation : System Engineer.

Project Title : AMEX – Export Blue (Team Lead)

Module : ECM (Enterprise Case Management)

Description: The Case Management initiative, which is a key component forth Service Delivery Unit (SDU), it delivers a disputes solution by providing

a platform that is best in class, hard to duplicate and scalable. The platform has leverage software provided by PegaSystems to create a flexible rules engine for handling customer disputes.

The SDU realizes an increase in productivity for dispute and fraud associates, increase in cross-sell revenue, increase in customer and employee satisfaction and reduction in point of contact handling time and write-offs.

Environment: J2EE, IBM Mainframe, PEGA and UDB-DB2

Team Size: 4

Client: American Express Project Role: System Developer

Responsibility:

Understanding Business requirements and functionality.

DB2- Data remediation on UDB-DB2.

Enhancement of existing programs according to Client specifications

Monitoring the installed jobs & providing support.

Coordination for the Integration of the Project and Unit, System Testing.

KPIT Cummins InfoSystems Ltd., Pune.

Duration : Jan. 2007 to Feb 2010. **Designation** : Sr. Software Engineer.

Project Title : "BestInfo2 Development and Support Bestseller"

Client : Bestseller A/S, Denmark.

Project Environment : JSP, JavaScript, HTML, Oracle, Struts, BC4J framework, JDeveloper

Duration : Jan. 2007 to Sep. 2009.

Roles and Responsibilities: Being a core team member of Outbound Logistics Team, worked for Development and Maintenance of BestPack V.3, PDA and Hub Address (Admin) modules.

These all modules are related to outbound activities at BestSeller's warehouses.

Client's Details: Bestseller A/S, Denmark, is a garments and accessories supplier company, having retail outlets across the world, like Italy, Germany, China and more.

BestInfo2 is a web based application which automates all the operations of BestSeller. It has several modules like sample order, warehouse, Inbound logistics, outbound logistics, EDI, PDA, Price portal, Interconnect and like.

Personal Details

Date Of Birth : 20 th June' 1978 Marital Status : Married

Marital Status : Married Sex : Male

Language known: English, Hindi, and Marathi.